PROFESSIONAL OVERVIEW

I am a highly skilled, design-oriented full-stack JavaScript Developer with extensive experience designing, developing and project managing complex modern JavaScript applications from concept to inception. Consistent and reliable with strong technical knowledge and a passion for learning and adapting to new technology, I use my full range of communication, leadership and technical skills to deliver bespoke multi-faceted projects within deadline both when working alone and as part of a larger team.

SKILLS

Modern JavaScript

React • Redux • Node.js • ES6 • Gatsby • Mocha/Chai • Electron • Webpack • Gulp • Lint • jQuery • AngularJS

HTML + CSS

Styled-components • CSS Modules • Bootstrap • Sass • Pug • Jade • Responsive & Mobile First Design • Handlebars • CSS Grid (Pure CSS)

Backend

Software Architecture • Node.js • MySQL / MariaDB • Elasticsearch • Logstash • Redis • Python • Vagrant • Ansible • AWS • Continuous Integration (Jenkins • Gitlab CI • Git • SVN) • IPTables Security • Strong TCP/IP and Networking Knowledge

UI / UX Design

Adobe XD • Figma • InVision

Integrations and APIs

Solutions Architect (Project analysis, task breakdown, documentation, wireframes, time estimates) • Agile & Scrum

ADDITIONAL SKILLS AND INTERESTS

- Expert knowledge at building large scalable Single Page Applications with Typescript, Node.js, React, Redux, ES6, Webpack
- Experience building responsive front-ends with Angular, AngularJS, HTML, CSS, SCSS/SASS, CSS Modules, GatsbyJS, jQuery
- Expert knowledge in building robust domain-driven backend APIs with Node.js, Express, Redis, Sequelize, MySQL, Mocha / Chai, MongoDB and AWS
- · Strong Linux networking and information security background
- Experience with other back-end technologies such as Java, ElasticSearch, Django and Ruby
- Proficient with design tools like Adobe XD, Figma, Invision
- Proficient with Linux, Vagrant, Ansible, VirtualBox, Docker
- Working knowledge of other JavaScript build tools such as Gulp, Grunt and Bower

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sept 2018 - Present

Aquent | Dev6 - Consultant

Consultant for several client projects in both a team and individual setting with a focus on front-end application architecture.

• Marine Magnetics: Angular development on the mobile-enabled web component of a client application to enable surveyors to observe the underwater landscape and uncover hidden underwater artifacts. Built with Angular 6. Web sockets and SCSS.

 Talkify: Cloud business-phone and calling platform. Built a drag and drop call-flow visualization with D3, which enables consumers to create their own complex call flows for their small businesses. Built with Angular 7, D3 and SCSS.

Technologies Used: Angular, D3, Typescript, SASS/SCSS, Vue.js, Web sockets

June 2016 - May 2018

Freelance Web Developer

Freelance solutions with a focus on full-stack web development using modern JavaScript technologies. Working for clients in Canada.

- Lynch Fluids: Solutions Architect and Lead Developer on business intelligence software that enables
 operators to determine the profitability of materials. Built with React.js, PHP
 and Slim Framework.
- **Health Espresso:** Solutions Architect for Health Espresso, a hybrid mobile application that enables the elderly to remember to take their medication. Enhanced the MVP in a separate contract by designing and implementing a drug-to-drug interaction microservice with NodeJS.
- A number of CMS-enabled porfolio websites for visual artists, makeup artists and designers created from wireframes using Adobe XD and then built on GatsbyJS.

Technologies Used: ES6, React.js, Redux, Node.js, GatsbyJS, MySQL, Adobe XD, PHP, Slim Framework, Bootstrap, JSON, jQuery, AJAX, HTML5, SASS & CSS3, AWS, Apache, Git, Vagrant

January 2016 - Present

Univiobs - Lead Developer

UnivJobs is SAAS enabling post-secondary students and recent graduates to connect with forward thinking employers through part-time work, internships, and entry-level jobs. I am currently working for Univjobs to improve the front-end UI/UX and deploy new features for their growing user base.

Notable Projects

univjobs.com - I built a fast, secure, SEO friendly, scalable and easy to maintain platform from wireframes that includes a user-friendly CMS with associated modules that included user management, media uploads and blogging. Built using React, jQuery, GatsbyJS, GraphQL.

app.univjobs.com - Separated the application from the CMS-enabled website. I developed a secure marketplace app which included a job board, ATS, message center, and enables employers to filter through students from over 60 post-secondary schools by skills, school and program. The implementation also included Facebook login, authentication with Redis and super-fast searching with Elasticsearch and MySQL FTS.

Technologies Used: ES6, React.js, Redux, Node.js, Express.js, GatsbyJS, GraphQL, MariaDB, Adobe XD, CSS Modules, Core CSS, Elasticsearch, AWS, Gitlab CI, Vagrant, Redis

May 2016 – August 2016 JavaScript Developer Pinnaca Toronto, ON

- Redesigned and developed outdated internal tools using AngularJS and Java.
- Worked in a team of two to create a file-diff application showing differences between CSV files using Angular and Talend for a Pinnaca client.
- Created an AngularJS authentication library for SSO-integrated apps.

Notable Project

Khalil Stemmler

ng-keycloak - Designed and developed an AngularJS authentication library for use with Keycloak, an open-source identity and access management solution, to integrate all of our in-house sites and internal tools with.

Technologies Used: React.js, Angular.js, Bootstrap, Node.js, Python, Salesforce

PREVIOUS EXPERIENCES

- Winter Intern at IBM Cognos BI resolving client service requests, 12 weeks in 2015.
- Worked on enhancing Jomar's proprietary ERP system as a Java/SQL Developer, 12 weeks.

EDUCATION

2018 B.Sc. in Computer Science, Brock University 2017 Dip. In Internet Communications Technology, Sheridan College

OTHER PROJECTS

<u>Glitchie</u>: Create your own glitch art (Java app, working on an web app version with React)

<u>Personal Music Player</u>: Online music player to listen to your own music (React, MongoDB, GatsbyJS).

<u>Asterisk PBX Notifications:</u> Hacking Asterisk PBX's AMI to send me notifications on missed calls.

<u>AWS SES Microservice:</u> Microservice for sending mail with AWS SES (NodeJS, Express, Mocha / Chai, Supertest).

For more, see my <u>portfolio</u> or ask for code samples. khalistemmler.com github.com/stemmlerjs linkedin/in/khalilstemmler